CHIRAG BARANDA

Software developer(Full-time)

A Graduate student in Software development & support, with experience and extensive education in software design and application development. A fast learner with multitasking skills. Experience as a technical specialist-L2 with strong troubleshooting and problem-solving skills with an analytical mindset. Strong work ethic in a team or individual setting to drive product success.

mail.info.chirag96@gmail.com

Hamilton, Canada

in linkedin.com/in/chiragbaranda

+1-(289)-922-8270

chiragbarandaofficial.wordpress.com

github.com/chiragmb96

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical SpecialistCanadian Tire Financial Services

01/2019 – 08/2019

Welland, ON

Experience

- Experienced as Level 2 Desk-side Support
- Experience of ticketing service Service Now
- Developed batch and power-shell scripts
- Software Deployment Using SCCM and Manual method
- Worked with Windows Server System
- Advanced Troubleshooting and Solution Documentation
- Worked in project for windows migration and testing
- Experienced working in Office 365 Migration

Application DeveloperBruminds Technocrats Pvt. Ltd.

biulillius reciliociats Pvt. Ltu

08/2016 – 03/2017 Responsibilities Ahmedabad, India

- Plan, test, and implement various Web-based applications using Java- servlet, Hibernate and JSP ,HTML, CSS, JS, SQL Server
- Developed a browser-based management system, allowing various documents to be placed in Windows Explorer interface folders.
- Developed security administration applications, controlling authority levels in database transactions and minimizing safety problems; partially implemented using Java.
- Assist in developing custom Web parts for application support toolset. Routinely troubleshoot issues and support internal users
- OTP implementation for self-Authentication

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming

Java, HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Python, C/C++, C#.Net, MVC/WEB-API, Basic React.is, Basic Wordpress, Basic Go

Operating system

Windows 7/8/10, Windows 7/10 server, Linux Ubuntu

Server Management

Microsoft System Center Configuration Manager(SCCM)

Database

SQL Server, Oracle, MS Access, Basic Vpshere & Azure

API used

Bing Map, Yelp, Basic REST

Software Applications

Net Beans , Sublime Text, Visual Studio, SQL Server, Katalon Recorder, Microsoft Office, Draw.io

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Mohawk College (09/2017 – 12/2019)

- Developed Windows applications using C#, Java, python
- Worked with Microsoft tools i.e Microsoft word/excel-VBA/Access/project
- Website Testing using Katalon Recorder
- Java Data structure and algorithm, Battleship strategy improvement

Tourist Helper Web App (09/2019 – 12/2019)

- A responsive web application designed for a tourist using following technologies - HTML | Bootstraps | Bing-Map | Yelp API
- Application allow user to find various places as per search criteria i.e Restaurants, Accommodation, Events, Hospitals and Police Station
- Application was designed to rate various places, like and comment from Tourist

Paint Program - A Desktop Application (Java)

- User can draw different objects by choosing a color and setting stroke width. Select, undo and delete operations can be applied on those objects.
- This application is a cumulative activity that will draw on many of the features of Java, OOP concepts and critical thinking.
- It was created using exception handling, event handlers, graphics, Java FX GUI components, inheritance, array list, polymorphism and implementation of both abstract and concrete classes.

Money-on-Click Web Application (08/2016 – 03/2017)

- A web application developed using Java-hibernate, Html,CSS, JSP, and Javascript. A single platform where there are two types of user for this web application. One who wants to pay and get work done and another who wants to work and get paid.
- Application has one time password implementation for new user registration and forgot password for both email and phone number

EDUCATION

Diploma in Computer system technician - Software support

Mohawk College 09/2017 - 12/2019

Hamilton, ON

Achievements

Two times Academic honor from dean

 Secured 1st rank in Bizcafe in Business fundamental

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering L.D. College of Engineering

08/2013 - 03/2017

Ahmedabad, India